Sahib Julka

 ${\it Machine Learning Scientist} \\ +49\ 1590\ 161\ 2115\ |\ {\it sahib.julka@yahoo.com}\ |\ \underline{\it Linkedin}\ |\ Google\ Scholar$

Summary

Creative problem solver with a strong background in Machine Learning domains such as Vision, Time-Series Signals, and Causal Inference. My PhD was on advancing Machine Learning tools in the application domain of Astrophysics and Planetary Science. I have also worked actively towards making Representation Learning more controllable and interpretable, as well as contributed in Deep Active Learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

| Programming Languages: Python | | | |
|--|--|--|--|
| Machine Learning Frameworks: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn | | | |
| Tools: MLOps, WandB, Git | | | |

EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

Apr. 2018 – Dec 2024

University of Passau, Germany

- Led Machine Learning in Europe-wide project on Planetary Science viz. Europlanet2024
- Taught Data Science Lab and Machine Learning Lab for 5 years
- Supervised numerous Masters and Bachelors Thesis
- Organised Hackathons and Convened Machine Learning Workshops/Conference Sessions

Student Researcher
Nov. 2017 – Jan 2018
University of Passau
Passau, Germany

• Developed Data Annotation tool

Machine Learning Engineer Upwork.com Aug. 2017 – Mar 2018 Passau, Germany

• Predictive modeling jobs

EDUCATION

| University of Passau | Passau, Germany |
|--|-------------------------------|
| PhD in Computer Science, Faculty of Computer Science and Mathematics | 2022 - 2024 |
| University of Passau MSc. Computer Science, Faculty of Computer Science and Mathematics | Passau, Germany 2015 - 2018 |
| VIT University Bachelors of Technology, School of Computer Science and Engineering | Vellore, India 2009 - 2013 |
| Departure Departure | |

Personal Details

Status: 32M, Single, German National (prev. Indian)

Languages: English (First), German (Fluent), Hindi (Fluent)

Hobbies: Music (Guitar, Vocals), Sports (Cycling, Weightlifting), Photography